A Guide to the Papers of Richard Watkins Carrington 1880-1933
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Legal Cases
  - A.K. Townsend 1928 (Box 67)
  - William Trigg 1922-1928 (Box 67)
  - W.O. Trimmer 1923 (Box 67)
  - Goodwin Turner 1925-1928 (Box 67)
  - Mary Tyler 1924-1928 (Box 67)
  - Miscellaneous "T" 1913-1932 (Box 67)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - General 1912-1925, 2 folders (Box 67)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - General 1926-1933, n.d., 3 folders (Box 68)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - William Carter, bankrupt 1921-1931, n.d., 3 folders (Box 68)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - J.W. Cunningham 1924-1925 (Box 69)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - S.L. Deaner 1926-1930 (Box 69)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - G.M. Garrett 1922-1928 (Box 69)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - Simon Girsh, bankrupt 1919-1922, 3 folders (Box 69)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - Simon Girsh, bnakrupt 1923-1926, n.d., 2 folders (Box 70)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - Highland Construction 1926-1928 (Box 70)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - Samuel Hodges 1923-1925 (Box 70)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - N.W. Hubard 1920-1926 Jan (Box 70)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - N.W. Hubard 1926 Feb-1930, n.d. (Box 71)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - A.S.B. James 1921-1929, n.d., 2 folders (Box 71)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - Luitwieler Cam Pump Co. 1925-1929 (Box 71)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - Maury Land Corporation 1923-1925 (Box 71)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - Hackley Morrison 1926-1928 (Box 72)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - Republic Land & Development Corporation 1924-1931, n.d., 3 folders (Box 72)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - Morris Solomon 1925-1926 (Box 72)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - Triumph Ice Machine Company 1922-1924 (Box 72)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - Robert Wallerstein 1924-1929 (Box 72)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - Allene B. Walker 1925-1926 (Box 72)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - Peter Warwick 1925-1930 (Box 72)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - Tucker Watkins 1926-1927 (Box 73)
  - Union Bank & Federal Trust - D.A. Weatherford 1925 (Box 73)
  - Union Securities Corporation (United Small Loan Corporation) 1923-1925 (Box 73)
  - Union Trust Company 1920 (Box 73)
  - Universal Film Exchange 1924 (Box 73)
  - Urban League of Richmond 1929-1930 (Box 73)
  - U.S. Leather Company 1920-1924, n.d., 2 folders (Box 73)
  - University of Virginia 1921-1931 (Box 74)
  - Sherman Woodson Van Hoof 1923 (Box 74)
  - Vany Realty Corporation 1924-1931, n.d., 3 folders (Box 74)
  - J.C. Varkentine 1932-1933 (Box 74)
  - Walter Veitch 1919-1922 (Box 75)
  - Virginia General Assembly 1923-1924 (Box 75)
  - Virginia-Carolina Chemical Company 1921-1922 (Box 75)
  - Virginia-Carolina Joint Stock Land Bank 1917-1923 (Box 75)
  - Virginia Coal Briquetting Company 1911-1918, n.d., 2 folders (Box 75)
  - Virginia Law Review 1914-1927 (Box 76)
  - Virginia Passenger & Power Company 1901-1909, n.d., 3 folders (Box 76)
  - Virginia State Bar Association 1926-1932, 3 folders (Box 77)
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce 1924-1928 (Box 77)
  - Virginia Trust Company 1916-1926, n.d. (Box 77)
  - Virginia Twenty-Nine Corporation 1929 (Box 77)
  - Virginia Union University 1925-1933 (Box 77)
  - M.G. Voris 1921-1922 (Box 78)
  - Miscellaneous "V" 1914-1931 (Box 78)
  - J.R. Wade 1922-1925 (Box 78)
  - Robert L. Wallerstein 1915-1929, n.d., 2 folders (Box 78)
  - H.J. Warthen 1920-1921 (Box 78)
  - Charles Watkins 1924-1931 (Box 78)
  - R.M. Weatherford 1919-1921 (Box 78)
  - L.R. Webster 1916-1917 (Box 78)
  - C.M. Weinbrunn 1917 (Box 79)
  - Wells Family 1813, 1923-1933, n.d., 5 folders (Box 79)
  - Westernoca Corporation 1926-1928 (Box 80)
  - C.W. Westervelt 1915-1916 (Box 80)
  - Mrs. William White 1922-1923 (Box 80)
  - William H. White, Jr., Attorney-at-Law 1924 (Box 80)
  - Wilson White 1912-1916 (Box 80)
  - Thomas Wilcox 1915-1921 (Box 80)
  - Ralph Wiley 1912-1917 (Box 80)
  - Frank D. Williams 1918-1921, n.d., 2 folders (Box 80)
  - C.E. Williamson 1926-1930 (Box 80)
  - Thomas Wills 1928-1929 (Box 80)
  - Wilmer & Vincent Corporation 1922-1930 Apr, 6 folders (Box 81)
  - Wilmer & Vincent Corporation 1930 May-1933, n.d., 6 folders (Box 82)
  - T.J. Wilson 1920 (Box 83)
  - Women's Club 1920-1931 (Box 83)
  - Samuel B. Woods 1920-1921 (Box 83)
  - Woodstock Iron & Steel Corporation 1910-1932, n.d., 2 folders (Box 83)
  - World Ticket & Supply Company 1927-1928 (Box 83)
  - Coleman Wortham 1921-1923 (Box 83)
  - Thomas Wyles 1927-1930 (Box 84)
  - Miscellaneous "W" 1912-1932 (Box 84)
  - A.G. Yarid 1915-1917 (Box 84)
  - Young Men's Christian Association 1923-1933, n.d., 2 folders (Box 84)
  - Miscellaneous "Y" 1916-1922 (Box 84)
  - Zero Products, Inc. 1925-1927 (Box 84)
- Estates
  - Estates - William Aitken 1914-1933, 2 folders (Box 85)
  - Estates - William Aitken - Financial & Legal Papers 1917-1919, n.d. (Box 85)
  - Estates - John Floyd Anderson 1915-1920 (Box 85)
  - Estates - Joseph P. Baker 1913-1916 (Box 85)
  - Estates - Georgia Beazley 1931-1932, 2 folders (Box 85)
  - Estates - A.B. Bellwood 1932 (Box 86)
  - Estates - Samuel Bland 1917-1921 (Box 86)
  - Estates - Nathaniel Bolling 1919-1920 (Box 86)
  - Estates - Channing Bolton, "Branchland" 1903-1933, 3 folders (Box 86)
  - Estates - Channing Bolton, "Branchland" n.d. (Box 87)
  - Estates - James N. Boyd 1928-1929 (Box 87)
  - Estates - John Branch 1930 (Box 87)
  - Estates - Alice Burton 1928-1930 (Box 87)
  - Estates - Thomas Bryan 1914-1920 (Box 87)
  - Estates - Thomas N. Carter 1918-1920, n.d., 2 folders (Box 87)
  - Estates - C.L. Dixon 1916-1922 (Box 88)
  - Estates - Matilda Dolfy [Dolphy?] 1918-1921 (Box 88)
  - Estates - V. Donati 1914-1918 (Box 88)
  - Estates - Arthur Einstein 1930-1932 (Box 88)
  - Estates - Joseph Farmer 1911-1916 (Box 88)
  - Estates - Mary Frison 1917-1920 (Box 88)
  - Estates - Harriet Grimes 1907-1914 (Box 88)
  - Estates - Thomas Gucker 1932 (Box 88)
  - Estates - J. Addison Hagan 1923-1924 (Box 88)
  - Estates - John Inglis 1921-1927 (Box 89)
  - Estates - Lizzie Jordan 1918 (Box 89)
  - Estates - Frederick Kell 1924-1929 (Box 89)
  - Estates - C.D. Langhorne 1919 (Box 89)
  - Estates - Frank B. Mealey 1922-1932, n.d., 2 folders (Box 89)
  - Estates - John Mills 1931 (Box 90)
  - Estates - Kate Morton 1920-1931 (Box 90)
  - Estates - Charles J. Murray 1927-1929 (Box 90)
  - Estates - John Orgain 1917-1918 (Box 90)
  - Estates - Alan Northwood 1915-1919 (Box 90)
  - Estates - John Pickrell 1890-1891, 1908-1921, 3 folders (Box 90)
  - Estates - John Pickrell 1922-1930, n.d., 2 folders (Box 91)
  - Estates - John Pickrell - bonds 1892-1925 (Box 91)
  - Estates - John Pickrell - tax returns 1913-1922, n.d. (Box 91)
  - Estates - H.N. Quisenberry 1907-1924, n.d., 2 folders (Box 91)
  - Estates - Joseph Redford 1923 (Box 92)
  - Estates - Pollie Robinson 1930-1931 (Box 92)
  - Estates - Emma & Bernard Samuels 1904, 1922-1933, n.d., 2 folders (Box 92)
  - Estates - Margaret Sargent 1923-1924 (Box 92)
  - Estates - Charles M. Shelton 1926-1927 (Box 92)
  - Estates - Cary Sheppard 1931-1933 (Box 92)
  - Estates - Josephine Solomons 1932 (Box 92)
  - Estates - Corydon Sutton 1932 (Box 92)
  - Estates - John Thompson 1927-1931 (Box 93)
  - Estates - Amanda Thorp 1926-1927 (Box 93)
  - Estates - Bessie McCaw Tompkins 1926 (Box 93)
  - Estates - Christopher Tompkins 1877-1927, n.d., 2 folders (Box 93)
  - Estates - W.P. Turner 1915-1918 (Box 93)
  - Estates - Willie Vest 1922-1933 (Box 93)
  - Estates - J. Robert Wade 1924-1931, n.d., 2 folders (Box 94)
  - Estates - J. Robert Wade - Financial Papers & Receipts 1922-1930, n.d. (Box 94)
  - Estates - Isabel Weisiger 1927 (Box 94)
  - Estates - George Wickham 1926-1931 (Box 94)
  - Estates - Charles Zehmer 1919-1921 (Box 94)
  - Estates - Miscellaneous 1930, n.d. (Box 94)
- Personal & Family Papers
  - Richard Carrington: Personal Papers & Correspondence
    - Richard W. Carrington 1909, 1912-1920, 6 folders (Box 95)
    - Richard W. Carrington 1921-1925, 5 folders (Box 96)
    - Richard W. Carrington 1926-1928, 4 folders (Box 97)
    - Richard W. Carrington 1929-1932 Sep, 5 folders (Box 98)
    - Richard W. Carrington 1932 Oct-1933, n.d., 2 folders (Box 99)
    - Richard W. Carrington - Business Diary 1920-1921 (Box 99)
    - Richard W. Carrington - Financial Papers & Receipts 1908-1926, 4 folders; arranged in chronological order by year only (Box 99)
    - Richard W. Carrington - Financial Papers & Receipts 1927-1933, n.d., 5 folders; arranged in chronological order by year only (Box 100)
    - Richard W. Carrington - General Assembly 1917 (Box 100)
    - Richard W. Carrington - General Assembly 1918-1919, n.d. (Box 101)
    - Richard W. Carrington - Investment Account with Davenport & Co. 1919-1930, arranged in chronological order by year only (Box 101)
    - Richard W. Carrington - Miscellaneous Papers 1914-1932, n.d. (Box 101)
      including genealogy, notices of meetings or the addition of new associates to law offices, invitations, certificates, etc.
    - Richard W. Carrington - Speeches & Addresses ca. 1911-1927, n.d., 2 folders (Box 101)
      including "Richmond in By-Gone Days," "O'Henry - His Life and Works," "Principles of Federalism As Exemplified in America," "The Function of Public Education," "The Segregation Ordinance Before the Richmond City Council"
  - Family Papers
    - A.B. Carrington 1929-1931 (Box 102)
    - Bessie Carrington 1918 (Box 102)
    - Betty Carrington 1916-1917 (Box 102)
    - Delia Davenport Carrington 1927-1933, 3 folders (Box 102)
    - Delia Davenport Carrington - Financial Papers & Receipts 1916,1925-1933, n.d. (Box 102)
      arranged in chronolgical order by year only
    - Delia Davenport Carrington - Investment Accounts 1926-1929, 2 folders (Box 102)
      arranged in chronological order by year only
    - Delia Davenport Carrington - Investment Accounts 1930-1932 (Box 103)
    - Emma & Mary Carrington 1932 (Box 103)
    - Henry P. Carrington 1915-1925 (Box 103)
    - John B. Carrington 1913-1914 (Box 103)
    - Laura Carrington 1919-1921 (Box 103)
    - Paul Carrington - Printed Sketch of His Life by Henry C. Riely 1928 (Box 103)
    - Tazewell Carrington 1905-1927 (Box 103)
    - William Tucker Carrington 1913-1915 (Box 103)
    - Anne Davenport 1919-1927 (Box 103)
    - Estate of Charles Davenport 1906-1932, 6 folders (Box 104)
    - Estate of Charles Davenport - Financial Papers & Receipts 1885-1933, n.d., 5 folders (Box 105)
    - Estate of Charles Davenport - Statements from Davenport & Co. 1924-1928, 2 folders (Box 106)
    - Estate of Charles Davenport - Stock Certificates 1889-1928 (Box 106)
    - Estate of Ellen McCaw Davenport 1923-1933, 3 folders (Box 106)
    - Estate of Ellen McCaw Davenport - Canceled Checks & Receipts ca. 1928-1931 (Box 106)
    - Estate of Ellen McCaw Davenport - Financial Papers & Receipts 1881-1931, n.d., 4 folders (Box 107)
    - Estate of Issac Davenport, Jr. 1914-1916 (Box 107)
    - Estate of Issac Davenport, Jr. 1917-1924 (Box 108)
    - Estate of Issac Davenport, Jr. - Financial Papers & Receipts 1888-1924, n.d., 3 folders (Box 108)
    - Estate of James B. McCaw 1906-1909 (Box 108)
- Bank Registers & Statements
  - Bank Statements - Bank of Commerce & Trusts 1931-1932 (Box 109)
  - Bank Statements - Miscellaneous 1922-1929 (Box 109)
  - Bank Statements - Planters National Bank 1915-1926, n.d., 4 folders (Box 109)
  - Bank Statements - Union Bank of Richmond [ca. 1924?] (Box 109)
  - Bank Statements - Union Bank & Federal Trust Company of Richmond 1927-1931 (Box 109)
  - Check Registers ca. 1913-1931, 2 folders & 13 volumes (Box 110)
  - Check Registers 1915-1928, 12 volumes (Box 111)
  - Check Registers 1924-1931 (Box 112)
  - Check Registers 1930-1933, 3 volumes (Box 113)
  - Passbooks for Estates of Carrington & Davenport Families ca. 1916-1931, 9 items (Box 113)
  - Passbooks for Richard W. and Delia Carrington ca. 1915-1933, 15 items (Box 113)
  - Passbooks for Estates of Non-Family Members, including: Pollie Robinson, C.L. Dixon, Cary Sheppard, W.R. Smith, J.E. Jenkins, Kate Morton, [L.R.] White, Walter Veitch, Emma Gray White, H.N. Quisenberry, and John Pickrell, also with two memoranda books ca. 1904-1933, 15 items (Box 113)
- Bound Volumes & Mini Tray Items
  - Journal of Richard W. Carrington 1927-1933 (Box 114)
  - Ledgers of Richard W. Carrington, with indexes 1915-1927, 2 volumes (Box 114)
  - Ledger of Home Owners Corporation Loans & Miscellaneous Loans, with index 1919-1933 (Box 115)
  - Ledger Transfer Book of Richard W. Carrington 1925-1930 (Box 115)
  - Letter book of John Pickrell, with index 1895-1914 (Box 115)
  - Memoranda Book of Loans by Home Owners Corporation 1920-1933 (Box 115)
  - Record Book of Dividend Checks for Charles Davenport's Estate 1928-1933 (Box 116)
  - Record Book of the Principal Account & Income Account for Charles Davenport Estate 1924-1925 (Box 116)
  - Record Book of the Principal Account, Legatee Account, Income Account, etc. of Isaac Davenport, Jr. Estate 1896-1902 (Box 116)
  - Check Register belonging to Charles Davenport 1906-1924
  - Day Books belonging to Richard Carrington 1915-1926, 3 volumes
  - Embossing Seals for R.W. Carrington Notary of the Public, the Collegiate School for Girls, the Glebe Estates, Inc., Dad's Inc., New Amsterdam Casualty Company and the Southern Briquette Coal Company n.d., 6 seals
  - Miscellaneous stampers used in Carrington's legal affairs n.d., 4 items
  - Kiwanis International Pin belonging to R.W. Carrington n.d.
  - 4 Victory Liberty Loan Payment Books 1919
  - 2 Illinois Central Railroad Coupon Books belonging to Isaac Davenport n.d.
- Oversize Folders
  - Plans for the Opening & Extension of Decatur Street from Vaden-Butler Property Line to and across Atlantic Coast Line Railroad Company's Right of Way, Richmond 1927-1928, 4 sheets (Folder 1)
  - Map of Wharf Property on the James River, Richmond, formerly belonging to Old Dominion Steamship Company [Richmond-New York Steamship Company} 1920, 2 sheets (Folder 1)
  - Plan for the Extension & widening of Streets south of Broad Street Road between Roseneath Road and the Corporation Line, Richmond 1922 (Folder 1)
  - Map of Powhatan Heights, Richmond, Virginia, and Chesterfield County, Virginia 1917 (Folder 1)
  - Simmons Company Property, Richmond, and all related drawings 1928, 21 sheets (Folder 1)
  - Suggested Scheme for Widening 14th Street from Main Street to Cary Street, Richmond 1928 (Folder 1)
  - Eastern Steamship Lines, Inc. Terminals revised arrangement of Buildings & Railroad Track 1928 (Folder 1)
  - May of Drewry Masion Addition in Chesterfield County, Virginia 1912 (Folder 2)
  - Plat of Mayo's Island, showing Proposed L & P Line and other maps of Mayo's Island showing a proposed street adjoining Mayo's Bridge, the Property of Richmond Baseball Park Corporation, and the conveyance from American National Bank to Jake Wells 1916-1924, 6 sheets (Folder 2)
  - Plan of Building at 209-11 Jasper Street, [Baltimore, Maryland?] and 216-18 North Eutaw Street, Baltimore, Maryland 1924, 4 sheets (Folder 2)
  - Map of Tracks of Land in New Kent County, Virginia, surveyed for Conveyance from St. John Du Val to the State Committee of Y.M.C.A. of Virginia 1925 (Folder 2)
  - Southern Railway System, Lines East, South Richmond, Virginia, Spur Track Serving the Simmons Company 1928, 2 sheets (Folder 2)
  - Property Map of the Country Club of Virginia, Henrico County 1928 (Folder 2)
  - Additional Simmons Company Property Showing Cross Section of the Track Hopper 1928 (Folder 2)
  - Unidentified Plans for a House, possibly R.W. Carrington n.d., 4 sheets (Folder 2)
  - Map of a Track of Land "Wilcox Neck" 1917, 4 sheets (Folder 3)
  - Copies of a Map of Powhatan Heights, Richmond & Chesterfield County, Virginia, by Atlantic Coast Realty Company 1919, 25 sheets (Folder 3)
  - Lands of T.M. Carrington in Mecklenburg and Lunenburg Counties, Virginia 1905 (Folder 5)
  - Map of Land in Chesterfield County, Virginia, purchased by T.M. Carrington from T.M. Cheatam 1914 (Folder 4)
  - Map of Property belonging to T.M. Carrington, Forest Hill, Richmond, Virginia 1921 (Folder 4)
  - Map of lots belonging to Lucile N. Miller, Richmond, Virginia 1921, 4 sheets (Folder 4)
  - Map of Property situated between Water Street and the James River, Ash Street and Gillies Creek, Richmond 1927, 3 sheets (Folder 4)
  - Plan for the Widening of Water and Maple Streets and the Closing of Parts of Wharf & Elm Street 1927 (Folder 4)
  - Homestead - R.W. Carrington, near Appomattox River for the division of the estate of Benjamin Phaup made in 1858 1928, 2 sheets (Folder 4)
  - Broad Street, Richmond 1929, 6 sheets (Folder 4)
  - Floor Plans for the home of [R.W. Carrington] n.d., 8 sheets (Folder 4)
  - Map of Homestead, Chesterfield County, Virginia, surveyed for E.D. Starke 1908, 2 sheets (Folder 5)
  - Revised May with Additions of Altavista, Property of Altavista Land & Improvement Company, Campbell County, Virginia 1913 (Folder 5)
  - Plan of Section of Alley Proposed to be Closed between Bainbridge Street & Brander Street, Richmond, and related Simmons Company drawings 1918-1919, 1928-1929, 5 sheets (Folder 5)
  - Plats to establish the property line between Franklin Street, [Richmond], and the Woman's Club 1922, 5 sheets (Folder 5)
  - Plats showing the land conveyed from the County Club of Virginia to the Fairway Ridge Corporation and from the Fairway Ridge Corporation to the Country Club of Virginia 1923, 3 sheets (Folder 5)
  - J.G. Carter to R.W. Carrington, Location of Lot off Rugby Road 1927 (Folder 5)
  - 4th Street Simmons Company Map showing Property Proposed to be acquired from Lelia C. Jewett & Mrs. Ida B. Lloyd, Richmond, Virginia 1928, 4 sheets (Folder 5)
  - First Floor Plan, South Elevation, and Second Floor Plan of an unidentified home n.d., 3 sheets (Folder 5)
  - Main Floor Plan of the First & Merchants National Bank of Richmond n.d. (Folder 5)
  - Broadside advertising property for sale at Powhatan Heights, by A.L. Adams, Agent, Richmond, Virginia n.d., 2 sheets (Folder 5)
  - Floor Plans of House and Cottages n.d. (Folder 5)
  - Plat of Property between 7th Street and Broad Street, Richmond 1913 (Folder 6)
  - Plat of Land on the corner of 5th Street and Marshall Street, Richmond, Virginia belonging to the Thalheimer Brothers 1917 (Folder 6)
  - Map of Property conveyed to United State Leather Company by Alexander S. Wright & Others, Richmond, Virginia 1920 (Folder 6)
  - Plat of the Cold Storage Property situated in Crozet, Albemarle County, Virginia, adjoining Miller School Property and W.[F?] Carter 1921 (Folder 6)
  - Plat of Land on the West Side of Forest Avenue South of Three Chopt Road, Henrico County, Virginia 1924 (Folder 6)
  - Plat of Property on the Northeast Corner of Garland Avenue and Brookland Park Boulevard, Richmond, Virginia 1924, 2 sheets (Folder 6)
  - Map showing Premises at 1008 & 1010 South Meadow Street and 2004 & 2006 Powhatan Street, Richmond, Virginia 1925 (Folder 6)
  - Map of Land north of Hungary Road and west of Laurel, Henrico County, Virginia, recently purchased by Jake Wells 1926, 4 sheets (Folder 6)
  - Plat of the "Kelly Tract," Henrico County, Virginia 1926, 3 sheets (Folder 6)
  - Plat surveyed for Republic Paper Products Corporation, Richmond, Virginia 1927 (Folder 6)
  - Map of Property to be conveyed by the Simmons Company to the Sanitary Felt Products Company, Inc. Richmond, Virginia 1929, 3 sheets (Folder 6)
  - Plat of No. 716 Franklin Street located on the Northeast Corner of Franklin and Laurel Streets, Richmond, Virginia 1929 (Folder 6)
  - Photograph of an unidentified college football squad n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Map of Lot No. 13 on Roselawn Road, Henrico County, Virginia n.d. (Folder 6)